<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joe Tower</title>
    <description>Design. Development. Music. Drupal. Opinions.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2014 15:56:46 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2014 15:56:46 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.1.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Recent Records</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;tommy-guerrero---no-mans-land&quot;&gt;Tommy Guerrero - No Man’s Land&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is another record very conducive to driving/coding/designing. I’ve just let it play all the way through once a day, for a week or so. I’m diggin it. I guess &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tommy_Guerrero&quot;&gt;Tommy Guerrero&lt;/a&gt; is one of those crazy rare talents - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rvca.com/t/anp-artist/tommy-guerrero&quot;&gt;skateboarder&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.asphaltduchess.com.mobilom.net/artists/tommy-guerrero/&quot;&gt;musician&lt;/a&gt;. What a combo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/asphalt-duchess/tommy-guerrero-locos-lament&quot;&gt;Listen to “Loco’s Lament”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;common---nobodys-smiling&quot;&gt;Common - Nobody’s Smiling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common&lt;/strong&gt; hasn’t released a truly awesome record in many years. After several listens, I still haven’t been able to appreciate &lt;em&gt;2007’s&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Finding Forever&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;2008’s&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Universal Mind Control&lt;/strong&gt; (least favorite, by far) or &lt;em&gt;2011’s&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The Dreamer, The Believer&lt;/strong&gt;. None of them had a single song that did anything for me. This is sad considering prior to this triple threat of awful, Common had been fairly consistent. I may be in the minority in having some level of apprecition for the eccentric &lt;em&gt;2002&lt;/em&gt; release &lt;strong&gt;Electric Circus&lt;/strong&gt;. I thought that record was a bit misdirected, but I really appreciate the huge risk and eclectic collection of music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nobody’s Smiling&lt;/strong&gt; is most impressive from a production standpoint. Every beat on here is pretty great - definitely the best since 2005’s &lt;strong&gt;Kayne&lt;/strong&gt;-centric &lt;strong&gt;Be&lt;/strong&gt; record. Common seems to have a rejuvinated sense of how to ride each beat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We were Chi-town’s Gangstarr
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rewind That&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;Common on him and No I.D. as a team&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Common seems more focused, lyrically, on this record. I attribute much of this to the refreshing return of &lt;strong&gt;No I.D.&lt;/strong&gt; on the production front. Common himself acknowledges this on &lt;strong&gt;Rewind That&lt;/strong&gt;. This is one of my favorite tracks (if not my favorite) on the record, so far. I’m a fan of nostalgia-driven lyrics like this - and, of course, deeply personal. This offers a look back at a very long and largely impressive career. Common reflects on Dilla’s final moments on earth, and his up and down relationship with No I.D. and several other collaborators, throughout his lengthy career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m digging these tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;No Fear&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Blak Majik&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Rewind That&lt;/em&gt;, and *&lt;em&gt;Young Hearts Run Free&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Deluxe edition, only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/commonns&quot;&gt;Listen to “Nobody’s Smiling”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-acid---liminal&quot;&gt;The Acid - Liminal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a sucker for a wicked falsetto, down-beat / haunting production, and ethereal vocals. It’s no surprise that I have found myself listening to this British trio’s record quite a bit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vocalist, &lt;strong&gt;Ry Cuming&lt;/strong&gt; has a &lt;strong&gt;Thom Yorke&lt;/strong&gt;-esque vocal delivery. Adam Freeland and Steve Nalepa have a mixed production style. The production is an odd mix of scratchy, almost drawn-out glitch, hollow drumb claps, casio keyboards and dancehall beats. I’m not sure how long my interest in this record will last, but I’m enjoying it right now. With records like this, headphones can make the record. The sparse production feels deliberate, and somewhat &lt;strong&gt;James Blake&lt;/strong&gt;-esque. At times you’ll hear &lt;strong&gt;XX&lt;/strong&gt;-like guitar swells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m digging these tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Animal&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Veda&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Ghost&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/the-acid-sounds&quot;&gt;Listen to “Liminal”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2014/07/recent-records</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2014/07/recent-records</guid>
        
        <category>recent records</category>
        
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        <category>reviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Appreciation for The Guthrie Theater</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;plays-performance-as-a-medium-to-convey-a-story&quot;&gt;Plays; performance as a medium to convey a story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been having a long email thread at work recently about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2014/7/9/5883669/christopher-nolan-says-theaters-can-survive-in-netflix-world&quot;&gt;Christopher Nolan’s comments regarding &lt;em&gt;content&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and more specifically, the medium by which content is packaged / conveyed to its audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Older than film is live action stories, or plays. Well, duh, but you know… connecting dots and keeping this post rolling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-guthrie-theater&quot;&gt;The Guthrie Theater&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My girlfriend and I received a $75 gift certificate to the &lt;a href=&quot;www.guthrietheater.org&quot;&gt;Guthrie&lt;/a&gt; last Christmas. Instead of spending the full amount on one &lt;em&gt;regular run&lt;/em&gt; ticket, we opted to purchase &lt;em&gt;preview&lt;/em&gt; show tickets; getting to see three shows instead of one. After seeing all three &lt;em&gt;preview&lt;/em&gt; shows, I’m not sure I would pay to see a &lt;em&gt;regular run&lt;/em&gt; show. Perhaps I’ll notice more nuanced and refined performance in the future – after I’m a more seasoned theater goer. But man, from what I’ve seen, it’s tough to fault preview shows at all. All three were exceptional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;crimes-of-the-heart&quot;&gt;1. Crimes of the Heart&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crimes_of_the_Heart&quot;&gt;View Wiki page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This story prompted many laugh-out-loud moments. I’m a big fan of single-environment stories - for example, &lt;strong&gt;Hitchcock’s&lt;/strong&gt; excellent &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rope_(film)&quot;&gt;Rope&lt;/a&gt;. This story holds your interest without more elaborate set work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-fair-lady&quot;&gt;2. My Fair Lady&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Fair_Lady&quot;&gt;View Wiki page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a fan of the 1938 film adaptation of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pygmalion_(play)&quot;&gt;Shaw’s classic Pygmalion&lt;/a&gt;, but the actual play is far superior. Admittedly, I have not seen the 1964 &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Fair_Lady_(film)&quot;&gt;film adaptation&lt;/a&gt; – hoping to remedy this negligence soon. From what I’ve heard, the 1964 film is a fairly line-by-line adaptation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were at the opening night of preview shows and the cast seemed absolutely spot-on perfect. The set was far more elaborate than either other play we saw. There was a drop-down piece in the center of the stage (a couch would sink and rise atop the dropped platform), and two revolving interior / exterior set pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a fan of some of the songs in this musical adaptation of Shaw’s story. My biggest issue with this version of Shaw’s classic is that the end drags quite a bit. Well, Pygmalion and My Fair Lady both suffer from the same end / resolve problem. I hate that Eliza ends up with Higgins. Critics and theater goers preferred this ending, and we now see it one way - at least, to my knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vanya-and-sonia-and-masha-and-spike&quot;&gt;3. Vanya and Sonia and Masha and Spike&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vanya_and_Sonia_and_Masha_and_Spike&quot;&gt;View Wiki page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was, hands down, our favorite and most enjoyable theater experience to date. Out of all three, this story kept us thoroughly entertained and laughing hysterically throughout the 2 hour run time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not familiar with &lt;strong&gt;Chekhov&lt;/strong&gt;’s work, but that did not detract from my enjoyment of the story. I found the dark humor hilarious, and will absolutely checkout Anton Chekhov’s work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;plays-are-pretty-awesome&quot;&gt;Plays are pretty awesome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could go on and on about how plays are a lost art form; under-appreciated by my generation and those younger than me. I’ll just say that I’m happy to have grown to appreciate the theater and look forward to years of new play experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2014/07/guthrie-theater</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2014/07/guthrie-theater</guid>
        
        <category>guthrie theater</category>
        
        <category>crimes of the heart</category>
        
        <category>my fair lady</category>
        
        
        <category>arts</category>
        
        <category>performance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dessa - Parts of Speech, Re​-​Edited</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;album-versus-the-re-imagined-re-edit&quot;&gt;Album versus the re-imagined re-edit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to Dessa’s debut (2010’s Badly Broken Code) companion record released one year after its release, 2011’s Castor the Twin, now 2013’s &lt;strong&gt;Parts of Speech&lt;/strong&gt; has a companion record, of sorts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These re-edits/children aren’t as radically different from their reinterpretation/parents as Castor’s are; you won’t find live instrument versions of any songs from Parts of Speech. Each remix is more tame, but very different from the original piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;love-for-the-remix&quot;&gt;Love for the remix&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I love about these remixes is that, for some odd reason, I’ve listened to and appreciated each interpretation almost more than the actual album versions. Perhaps I find these reinterpretations less serious and more fun than the actual album versions? For whatever reason, some of these remixes are incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fighting-fish&quot;&gt;Fighting Fish&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Zeno’s arrow / never hits the mark / It’s always / hanging there over its shadow /safe from battle / waste of arch - / er’s time and trouble / waste of effort / waste of parts / If you don’t aim for the center / it’s a waste of the art”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This chorus murders my ears and echos for days. I’m not sure why this presentation helped me appreciate the album version, but I’m happy it did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;warsaw&quot;&gt;Warsaw&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“And I’m still living by my maiden name / The name I came with / The name I made / And I’m bare-faced at your masquerade”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of my favorite tracks from Parts of Speech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cecil’s Version&lt;/strong&gt;
I really adored the album’s original beat. It was one of the few beats on the record that I loved the first time I heard it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cecil’s version is pretty unreal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Budo’s Version&lt;/strong&gt;
I love what Budo did with this remix. It is &lt;strong&gt;so&lt;/strong&gt; great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;call-off-your-ghost&quot;&gt;Call Off Your Ghost&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Committee (Lazerbeak x Ryan Olson) remix is a lot easier to listen to than the album version. This chorus killed me, in a bad way, on the album. Here I find it pretty great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-only-me&quot;&gt;It’s Only Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two remixes of this found here. I prefer the &lt;strong&gt;Year of the Horse&lt;/strong&gt; version over the &lt;strong&gt;Grant Cutler&lt;/strong&gt; mix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;skeleton-key&quot;&gt;Skeleton Key&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is, by far, my least favorite Dessa song. The hook is catchy, sure, but it’s also repeated an uneccesarliy high amount of times throughout the song. I’d count each time it’s mentioned, but it’s like nails on a chalkboard to me. I can’t do that to myself. I hate this chorus. The remix does the song a great service by not echoing the chorus ad nauseam. So, yay?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dessa-the-poet&quot;&gt;Dessa the poet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dessa is a brilliant writer, and even better at singing and rapping her own words. Her lyrics are second to few artists. Now I’ll have to go back and revist Parts of Speech with a fresh perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dessa.bandcamp.com/album/parts-of-speech-re-edited&quot; title=&quot;Buy Dessa&#39;s Parts of Speech Re-Edited&quot;&gt;Buy Dessa’s re-edited album - $4.99&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2014/06/dessa-parts-of-speech-remix</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2014/06/dessa-parts-of-speech-remix</guid>
        
        <category>dessa</category>
        
        <category>remixes</category>
        
        <category>doomtree</category>
        
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        <category>reviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tycho - Awake</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been listening to this record more consistently than anything else released this year, so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;awake-is&quot;&gt;Awake is:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;great-for-running--exercise&quot;&gt;Great for running / exercise&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some electronic music (very generalized genre description, I know) intrinsically has the ability to showcase peaks and valleys, rhythmic rise and fall, and hypnotic comfort grooves. &lt;strong&gt;Tycho&lt;/strong&gt; has mastered this, and the universal appeal of his music is testament enough. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-best-for-designing-and-coding-what&quot;&gt;The best for designing &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; coding. what!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It just is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-best-driving-music&quot;&gt;The best driving music&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go ahead, get in your car, start this record up on repeat, and drive.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2014/03/tycho-awake</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2014/03/tycho-awake</guid>
        
        <category>tycho</category>
        
        <category>iso50</category>
        
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        <category>reviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Negril, Jamaica</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;travel&quot;&gt;Travel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travel has been at the forefront of life goals over the past few years. &lt;strong&gt;Jamaica&lt;/strong&gt; was decided upon rather spontaneously, while researching travel destinations. As always, vacations boil down to price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;negril&quot;&gt;Negril&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For two travellers, &lt;strong&gt;Negril, Jamaica&lt;/strong&gt; can be as low as $1,400 for 6 days (5 nights) roundtrip airfare, and resort/b&amp;amp;b accommodations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of our stay was spent wondering the West End, on foot, seeking out delicious food and memorable conversation. Thankfully, both were plentiful. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resort-experience&quot;&gt;Resort experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are those who travel seeking a hands-free, beach-bound, do nothing, be served, type of refreshing/recharging vacation. I affectionately refer to these people as “beach people”. I fall into another bucket/term called “explorer”. I appreciate the beach, but can only handle it for small amounts of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My girlfriend and I prefer an authentic cultural experience when travelling. We chose to stay in the cliffs over the beach because we’re not beach people, but we’d like to stay in close proximity, if we’re inclined to go. The deciding factor in our resort choice was whether or not it was Jamaican-owned. Too many resorts in Jamaica are internationally-owned. They may be great resorts; employing Jamaicans, offering steller views, but some discourage exploring off-compound local businesses. They may not give the traveller an authentic experience when it comes to food. Some (Sandles) use scare tactics to keep wary travellers on their beach front property compound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My experience at Negril Escape led me to start reviewing places on
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tripadvisor.com/ShowUserReviews-g147313-d596160-r193597449-Negril_Escape_Resort_Spa-Negril_Westmoreland_Parish_Jamaica.html#CHECK_RATES_CONT&quot;&gt;Trip Advisor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-food&quot;&gt;The food&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had some truly incredible food experiences. Here are the highlights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/jamaica/ras-rody.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ras Rody&#39;s Food Cart&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ras-rodys-organics&quot;&gt;Ras Rody’s Organics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A bit of food and philosophy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our second day in Jamaica prompted our first on foot exploration. Having read about Ras Rody and his food cart, I knew that he was not supposed to be maning his “Ras Rody’s Organic” truck during the week we were here. Man, I’m glad his week-long retreat was cancelled, and we were able to meet him. Ras Rody divides his time between being a cook at a restaurant in the United States some odd months out of the year, and living in Jamaica running the food truck with his Son Shadrach, the remainder of months out of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat down on one of two small benches lining the food truck, immediately piqued by what we were smelling. Ras Rody seems like a genuinely nice gentleman. His smile is unforgettable. His food and conversation are legendary. I very much hope our paths cross again some day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/jamaica/ras-rody-food.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ras Rody&#39;s Delicious Food&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/jamaica/pablo-restaurant.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pablo Restaurant&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pablo-restaurant&quot;&gt;Pablo Restaurant&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was dark and rainy, and we desperately needed food. We hailed a cab and asked the driver to take us to a place we read about called The Rough House. Having been in Jamaica for a few days at this point, we somewhat knew the general area in which this restaurant was supposed to be. We turned off the main road into residential territory, and I was a bit confused - as again, we kind of knew where we were supposed to be and our surroundings were not that. After navigating some, we arrived at a somewhat sketchy looking house, adorning a sign that read “The Rough House”. I asked the driver, “we’re looking for a restaurant called The Rough House. This does not look like a restaurant”. He thought for a moment, and said “Okay, I think I know where that place is”. We returned to the cab, still holding on to that unclear idea of where this mythical Rough House eatery may or may not be. So after heading back in the direction we felt this restaurant was, alas, no restaurant. We did drive by a place called “Pablo Restaurant”, which we had walked past a day or two before this experience, and told the driver to turn around and drop us there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long journey, and some meandering storyline later, we enjoyed our favorite meal in Jamaica. My girlfriend chose a garlicy pasta dish, aptly called “Rasta Pasta”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/jamaica/pablo-restaurant-rasta-pasta.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pablo Restaurant&#39;s Rasta Pasta&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose the vegetarian platter which was very colorful. It was full of callaloo, cabbage, possibly Scotch-Bonnet peppers and more, served with beans and rice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/jamaica/pablo-restaurant-vegetarian-platter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pablo Restaurant&#39;s Rasta Pasta&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-full-day-of-exploration&quot;&gt;A full day of exploration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of our 6 days, we chose one to pack full of planned activity. Our airport taxi service Clives Auto Trasfer, offered a tour package. A driver would spend the day with you and drive you to three different activity destinations. We chose the Black River, YS Falls, and Appleton Estate Rum Factory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;black-river&quot;&gt;Black River&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crocodiles, birds, mangrove trees, oh my.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/jamaica/black-river.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Black River&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/jamaica/black-river-crocodile.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Black River Crocodile&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/jamaica/black-river2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Black River 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/jamaica/black-river3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Black River 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/jamaica/black-river-mangrove.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Black River - Mangrove Trees&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ys-falls&quot;&gt;YS Falls&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cool springs, layered pools and falling water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/jamaica/ys-falls.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;YS Falls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/jamaica/ys-falls2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;YS Falls 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/jamaica/ys-fuzzy-tree.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;YS Falls - Fuzzy Tree&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;appleton-estate&quot;&gt;Appleton Estate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never knew rum could be so good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/jamaica/appleton-estate.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Appleton Estate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/jamaica/appleton-estate-distillery.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Appleton Estate Distillery&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/jamaica/appleton-estate-pouring.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Appleton Estate Pouring Rum&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;goodbye&quot;&gt;Goodbye&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It always sucks leaving places you love. Some day we may find ourselves back in Jamaica. I very much recommend vacationing in the cliffs, if you’re the type of person who loves to explore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/jamaica/cliff-tree.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cliff Tree&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/jamaica/ackee.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ackee fruit in a tree&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/jamaica/sunset.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset from Negril Escape&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2014/03/jamaica-trip</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2014/03/jamaica-trip</guid>
        
        <category>jamaica</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Top 15 Albums of 2013</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2013/15-justin-timberlake-2020.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#15 Justin Timberlake - The 20/20 Experience&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;justin-timberlake---the-2020-experience&quot;&gt;#15 Justin Timberlake - The 20/20 Experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-mirrors-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Mirrors&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/89052506&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first half of this album is unquestionably superior to the second. &lt;strong&gt;Timberlake&lt;/strong&gt; can be too long-winded in execution ; some of these long compositions feel forced, and unnatural. What we have is a very ambitious double record. Timberlake won me over with 2007s incredible &lt;em&gt;FutureSex/LoveSounds&lt;/em&gt; and I was worried he’d never record another album; instead focusing on music. I’m happy he came back. Next time I hope he favors quality over quantity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Pusher Love Girl&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Strawberry Bubblegum&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Gimme What I Don’t Know (I Want)&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Mirrors&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2013/14-stomach-earth-st.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#14 Stomach Earth - S/T&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stomach-earth---st&quot;&gt;#14 Stomach Earth - S/T&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-watchers-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Watchers&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/89021618&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crushing doom record of the year! This is one hell of a debut. I’m not really sure what else to say about this record except it’s pretty great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Void Angel Ritual&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Watchers&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The One They Fear&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2013/13-neko-case-worse-things-get.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#13 Neko Case - The Worse Things Get, The Harder I Fight, The Harder I Fight, The More I Love You&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;neko-case---the-worse-things-get-the-harder-i-fight-the-harder-i-fight-the-more-i-love-you&quot;&gt;#13 Neko Case - The Worse Things Get, The Harder I Fight, The Harder I Fight, The More I Love You&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-night-still-comes-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Night Still Comes&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/105607943&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neko Case has released, possibly, the most personal record of her career. She writes from a very depressed place; offering insight into the horrors of parenting (&lt;em&gt;Nearly Midnight, Honolulu&lt;/em&gt;), and the neglect and indifferent feelings about the passing of her own parents(&lt;em&gt;Man&lt;/em&gt;). I love Neko’s voice and this record is nothing short of awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I’m From No Where&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Man&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Nearly Midnight, Honolulu&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2013/12-chvrches-bones-of-what-you-believe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#12 Chvrches - The Bones of What You Believe&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;chvrches---the-bones-of-what-you-believe&quot;&gt;#12 Chvrches - The Bones of What You Believe&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-gun-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Gun&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/94123129&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year’s list is definitely full of debut records from exciting new artists. In the battle of female-fronted debut albums, this Scottish trio &lt;strong&gt;Chvrches&lt;/strong&gt;, the American four-piece &lt;strong&gt;Haim&lt;/strong&gt; and British trio &lt;strong&gt;London Grammar&lt;/strong&gt; are no exceptions. This number twelve spot was a toss up between three exceptional records, which is why I pointed out London Grammar and Haim. Chvrches won me over with Lauren Mayberry’s fantastic vocals, the 80s synth-heavy compositions, crushing beats, and my general love for electronic music. I’m a sucker for records like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Mother We Share&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Gun&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Science/Visions&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2013/11-darkside-psychic.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#11 Darkside - Psychic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;darkside---psychic&quot;&gt;#11 Darkside - Psychic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-paper-trails-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Paper Trails&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/110945653&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been my favorite record to listen to while working. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.darksideusa.com/&quot; title=&quot;Darkside’s Website&quot;&gt;Darkside&lt;/a&gt; is a collaboration project between &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Darkside_(band)&quot; title=&quot;Wiki on Darkside&quot;&gt;Nicholas Jaar and Dave Harrington&lt;/a&gt;. I adore the funky, dark, multi-instrument infused beats mixed with lush, almost Peter Gabriel-like vocals. This record has kept me moving all year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Golden Arrow&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Paper Trails&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Freak, Go Home&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2013/10-arcade-fire-reflektor.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#10 Arcade Fire - Reflektor&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;arcade-fire---reflektor&quot;&gt;#10 Arcade Fire - Reflektor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-here-comes-the-night-time-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Here Comes The Night Time&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/114965236&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first heard the title track on the radio, I wasn’t impressed. Then I heard/watched their odd &lt;a href=&quot;http://pitchfork.com/news/52465-arcade-fire-debuted-three-new-tracks-on-post-snl-nbc-concert-special/&quot; title=&quot;Arcade Fire Special&quot;&gt;half hour post-SNL special&lt;/a&gt;, and found myself a bit more interested. This record took some time to appreciate. It’s ambitious sound new sounding, but yet, still refreshes and retains some of the magic that made 2010’s &lt;strong&gt;Suburbs&lt;/strong&gt; release so special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Reflektor&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Here Comes The Night Time&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;It’s Never Over (Oh Orpheus)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2013/9-the-national-trouble-will-find-me.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#9 The National - Trouble Will Find Me&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-national---trouble-will-find-me&quot;&gt;#9 The National - Trouble Will Find Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-sea-of-love-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Sea of Love&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/126240539&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere between 2007’s &lt;strong&gt;The Boxer&lt;/strong&gt; and 2010’s &lt;strong&gt;High Violet&lt;/strong&gt; I fell in love with these indie rockers. Vocalist &lt;strong&gt;Matt Berninger&lt;/strong&gt; has a unique, sometimes brooding voice. Even more impressive is his odd cadence and phrasing of words. The way he adjusts his voice to fit each composition (or visa versa) is truly distinct. The National have release another great album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Sea of Love&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Graceless&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Pink Rabbits&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2013/8-polica-shulamith.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#8 Polica - Shulamith&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;polica---shulamith&quot;&gt;#8 Polica - Shulamith&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-smug-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Smug&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/112233384&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many sophomore records before it, this one didn’t grab me like their debut. I really hoped that Channy’s beautiful and vocorded/autotuned vocals weren’t a one-trick pony. It took me some time with their debut record to appreciate her voice being aided and re-imagined through the use of technology. I was a big fan of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.startribune.com/entertainment/music/104092628.html&quot; title=&quot;Roma di Luna&quot;&gt;Roma di Luna&lt;/a&gt;, specifically favoring Channy’s angelic voice and reserved stage presence. In Polica, and maybe because of her sectionorce (pure speculation), she seems to have a renewed sense of power and confidence. I love seeing that confidence in talented people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Chain My Name&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Smug&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Tiff&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2013/7-volcano-choir-repave.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#7 Volcano Choir - Repave&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;volcano-choir---repave&quot;&gt;#7 Volcano Choir - Repave&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-byegone-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Byegone&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/101164310&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Justin Vernon&lt;/strong&gt; is no stranger to critical acclaim, and even though &lt;strong&gt;Bon Iver&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://pitchfork.com/news/47962-justin-vernon-bon-iver-winding-down/&quot; title=&quot;Pitchfork on Bon Iver’s Future&quot;&gt;might be no more&lt;/a&gt;, this record once again proves he can re-invent himself. I know I’ll always eagerly await any project he’s involved in. He’s just that kind of artist to me. I hope he works with Peter Gabriel in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Tiderays&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Acetate&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Alaskans&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2013/6-drake-nothing-was-the-same.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#6 Drake - Nothing Was The Same&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;drake---nothing-was-the-same&quot;&gt;#6 Drake - Nothing Was The Same&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-the-language-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;The Language&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/112824761&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nothing Was The Same&lt;/em&gt; wasn’t as appreciated on first-tenth listen, as Drake’s previous albums had been. Given time, this album grew on me significantly over the course of 2013. It’s still not up there with 2010’s &lt;strong&gt;Thank Me Later&lt;/strong&gt; or 2011’s &lt;strong&gt;Take Care&lt;/strong&gt;, but it’s a welcomed third (proper) record. I’m not sure where Drake is going from here, but I’ll probably like that record too. Once again, Drake doesn’t really say anything lyrically, but man can he sell it to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Tuscan Leather&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Hold On, We’re Going Home&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Language&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2013/5-atoms-for-peace-amok.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#5 Atoms For Peace - AMOK&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;atoms-for-peace---amok&quot;&gt;#5 Atoms For Peace - AMOK&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-ingenue-live-version-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Ingenue&lt;/em&gt;” (live version) from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/90786203&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The debut record from this &lt;strong&gt;Thom Yorke&lt;/strong&gt;-centered supergroup does not disappoint. The nine tracks exhibited here are intimate and focused. &lt;em&gt;Ingenue&lt;/em&gt; is one of my favorite Thom Yorke vocal performances ever, period. I adore everything about it - from the perfect vocal delivery to the lethargic and emotive composition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way, this album feels like a Thom Yorke follow-up to his 2006 debut album, &lt;strong&gt;The Eraser&lt;/strong&gt;, but with &lt;strong&gt;Flea&lt;/strong&gt; along for the ride. The beauty I find in both records comes down to the simple compositions that take time to sink in. Both records have fueled me through several painting sessions (acrylic paintings), and they will likely fuel several more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Before Your Very Eyes..&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Ingenue&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Stuck Together Pieces&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2013/4-chelsea-wolfe-pain-is-beauty.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#4 Chelsea Wolfe - Pain Is Beauty&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;chelsea-wolfe---pain-is-beauty&quot;&gt;#4 Chelsea Wolfe - Pain Is Beauty&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-the-waves-have-come-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;The Waves Have Come&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/105452578&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like a fine wine, this is the kind of record you let swirl around, letting the complexity sink-in and re-define your pallet. She is an incredibly talented vocalist and composer. The layers are so dense, so rich, that it takes time for each composition to take hold of you. These songs being performed by a less capable artist would’t really work. Chelsea has a unique vision and the ability to execute that vision. The result showcases unreal passion, beauty, control, and restraint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I adore everything about Chelsea and this record. Favorite female vocalist of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Feral Love&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;We Hit A Wall&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Waves Have Come&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2013/3-earl-sweatshirt-doris.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#3 Earl Sweatshirt - Doris&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;earl-sweatshirt---doris&quot;&gt;#3 Earl Sweatshirt - Doris&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-chum-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Chum&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/66222899&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chum&lt;/em&gt; Is hands-down my favorite hip-hop track of the year. I’ve listened to it countless times and still think it’s one of the dopest songs in years. Especially that beat. Sick!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thebe became an urban legend with his 2010 debut mixtape &lt;strong&gt;Earl&lt;/strong&gt;, and his absence from the real world only heightened fan appreciation and expectation. &lt;strong&gt;Doris&lt;/strong&gt; might not have lived up to those expectations, in the eyes of some, but to me, it’s kind of perfect. It still glamorizes some of the adolescent themes of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Earl_(mixtape)&quot; title=&quot;Earl&quot;&gt;2010’s Earl&lt;/a&gt;, but does so with a level of maturity not apparent three years ago. Releasing this kind of record at 19, I can only imagine what kind of record a 30 year old Thebe is capable of executing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doris&lt;/strong&gt; is, lyrically, my favorite hip-hop record of the year. Earl layered the wordplay on thick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Burgundy&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Chum&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Hive&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2013/2-kanye-west-yeezus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#2 Kanye West - Yeezus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;kanye-west---yeezus&quot;&gt;#2 Kanye West - Yeezus&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-im-in-it-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;I’m In It&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/108362666&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This album landed at number one on several year-end best of lists. It almost landed at number one on my list too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret that Kanye is a douche; an angry, confused, little boy. Most of the time he’s better off not speaking in public. He ends up making things worse for himself. The world may never understand Kanye West, the man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kanye is a genius, and I feel like his genius is misunderstood because he has no clue how to interact with the regular world. You know, those of us who live on the outside of KayneLand. Those of us who aren’t black and attempting to have a substantial career in the fashion industry. Those of us who create the best hip-hop record of 2013 and find reasons to whine about how we’re not taken seriously for….fashion. WHAT?! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Kanye isn’t is a great lyricist. He’s actually pretty damn awful. Double entendres and racist-fueled hate rants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kanye destroys me with his ability to craft beats and sell me on the fact that he believes his anger is justified. This record is a fucking &lt;strong&gt;monster&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s angry, unapologetic, and confusingly hate-fueled. I’m not quite sure why Kanye is so angry, but man does it make this record unreal. I feel like he overcompensates for lack of lyrical ability or having anything of real substance to say, by yelling loudly and convincing us this anger is rational. It’s entirely possible that Kanye has been discriminated against in some way (though he seems to be and have always been part of a more privileged class throughout his entire life) and maybe that one experience was all the fuel he needed to make such an angry record. I’m left scratching my head pondering what event could have been the catalyst in producing such an angry album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Everything on this beast&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2013/1-james-blake-overgrown.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#1 James Blake - Overgrown&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;james-blake---overgrown&quot;&gt;#1 James Blake - Overgrown&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-retrograde-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Retrograde&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/78709502&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I adored &lt;strong&gt;James Blake’s&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/music/reviews/2011/02/13/james-blake-self-titled-album-review/&quot; title=&quot;James Blake - Self-Titled Review&quot;&gt;debut album&lt;/a&gt; and couldn’t wait for a follow-up. He is one of the most exciting artists to emerge in the last 5 years. It seems like he’s only getting better with each release - evolving at an incredible pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the type of artist that makes me appreciate every second of their work, and hungrily await the next installment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Overgrown&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Retrograde&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Our Love Comes Back&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/2014/01/top-15-albums-of-2013</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2014/01/top-15-albums-of-2013</guid>
        
        <category>top albums of the year</category>
        
        <category>best albums of 2013</category>
        
        <category>top albums of 2013</category>
        
        <category>album reviews</category>
        
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        <category>reviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Earth - Revisited</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I haven’t painted, with any kind of consistency, since 2007 or so. 2005 through 2007 were huge years for me; in developing style, color theory, texture techniques, etc. The overarching kind of technique or thought process, which still sticks with me, is that of monochromatic color schemes. My style has always been abstract (likely always will be) and kept to a reserved color palette. I’m a big fan of texture combined with several values of a chosen color. It is the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/earth/earth-series-full.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Painting series photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;earth-series&quot;&gt;Earth Series&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2006 I completed an intensely textured series of paintings I called simply Earth. There was &lt;a href=&quot;http://tao-of-now.deviantart.com/art/Earth-Part-One-44917089&quot; title=&quot;Earth: Part One&quot;&gt;Part One&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://tao-of-now.deviantart.com/art/Earth-Part-Two-45704078&quot; title=&quot;Earth: Part Two&quot;&gt;Part Two&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://tao-of-now.deviantart.com/art/Earth-Part-Three-47894514&quot; title=&quot;Earth: Part Three&quot;&gt;Part Three&lt;/a&gt;. There was a Part Four that I never uploaded anywhere, mainly because I wasn’t proud of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a lot of time texturizing them, and never thought how insane it would be to try to actually paint anything on top of all that mess. The end result fell short of what I envisioned the series being. This was a great idea, and ultimately poor execution; bringing about cause to revisit this series. I loved the texture so much that I had to refine the execution; in an effort to better appreciate the end product. I am really happy with this series now, and feel proud to have them on my walls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After years of not painting, this was a great series to revisit and resume my forever sporadic painting career.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/2013/11/earth-revisited</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2013/11/earth-revisited</guid>
        
        <category>earth</category>
        
        <category>acrylic painting</category>
        
        
        <category>painting</category>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I&#39;m a Technology Nerd</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure when it happened, but I’ve been a nerd about technology for the majority of my adult life. Some of it goes hand-in-hand with being in the internet field, some in being a designer, and everything with being passionate about new stuff. But, to me, “nerd” isn’t derogatory. It’s the opposite; it’s a term that aims to succinctly capture passion, intelligence, and a unique kind of cultural qualifier in one little word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve hesitated to write about tech-related things because &lt;a href=&quot;http://verge.com&quot; title=&quot;The Verge&quot;&gt;The Verge&lt;/a&gt; does a better job than I ever could. I also admire their design team, for the most part. But, even though I listen to (and/or watch) the &lt;a href=&quot;http://twit.tv/&quot; title=&quot;This Week in Tech&quot;&gt;TWiT network&lt;/a&gt; (especially &lt;a href=&quot;http://twit.tv/show/all-about-android/&quot; title=&quot;All About Android on TWiT&quot;&gt;All About Android&lt;/a&gt;), and consume all tech everything on YouTube and Google Plus, I still have something unique to say. I am nothing without opinions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;apple&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I exclusively use Apple’s still unmatched Mac Book Pros, and still love OS X. I’m adamantly opposed to using any laptop that isn’t a Mac. Most of that has to do with my profession, but also because OS X’s file management has always made way more sense to me than any alternative. So awesome, I love Apple-made computers. Ugh, except that new MacPro garbage can. WTF?!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t owned an iPhone since the 3G. I’ve planned on purchasing an iPhone since the 4S was announced. I remember watching the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/apple-events/&quot; title=&quot;Apple Events&quot;&gt;Apple Keynote&lt;/a&gt; events for the 4S, the 5, and most recently the 5S/5C - and arriving at one conclusion: I will buy a new iPhone. Ultimately, I have always given-in to the better half of my rational mind. The iPhone’s camera has always brought me ever-so-close to pulling the trigger, but alas, iOS set in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ios&quot;&gt;iOS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When iOS7 was announced, I said to myself…
&amp;gt; Finally, Apple has redesigned iOS. It’s about damn time. Maybe I’ll…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope. The too-little/too-late updates were not enough to bring me back. Sure, iOS &lt;em&gt;feels&lt;/em&gt; better than ever, but it has still not changed, really. It’s kind of ugly; having some truly disgusting icons, and possibly not as intuitive as it once was. Sure, it’s still the same polished turd it’s always been, at its heart. I feel like Apple has lost that brilliant glimmer that once so proudly excelled at &lt;em&gt;“giving people what they didn’t know they needed”&lt;/em&gt;. A somewhat odd redesign isn’t enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iOS aside, I just don’t use Apple’s services/applications. Therefore, I can’t benefit from their proprietary goodness. iOS will, likely, forever be my go-to tablet choice. The iPad is tough to beat. But again, that same OS is unusable, for me, when it comes to phones. I realize that sounds ridiculous. I don’t care. I’m serious about phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really want to use an iPhone, but I just can’t. Before its formal announcement, the 5C was primed to be my next shiny new gadget. But not for more than the heavily speculated (and very realistic) $350-$400 off-contract price. I’m not sure how the tech world fooled itself into thinking a $400 iPhone would ever be a reality. Alas, $649 (32GB) for the “cheap” iPhone. WTF!? No way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hi, my name is Joe. I can’t use an iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;google&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For lack of better introductory sentence about Google, &lt;strong&gt;Google&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; insane. Where Apple succeeds in hardware &amp;amp; software integration, Google succeeds in better execution, reliability, and consistently innovative design.  Gmail/Youtube/Drive work very well, and for the most part, &lt;em&gt;look&lt;/em&gt; the same anywhere I use them (iOS, Android and via the web). There is still some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2013/1/24/3904134/google-redesign-how-larry-page-engineered-beautiful-revolution&quot; title=&quot;Unifying Holo and Kennedy&quot;&gt;Holo versus Kennedy&lt;/a&gt; elements that aren’t as consistent as they can be, yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google’s biggest challenge is getting anyone but technology nerds to appreciate vanilla Android. Cue, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2013/11/5/5069310/the-nexus-5-isnt-pure-android-its-pure-google&quot; title=&quot;The Verge on Pure Google&quot;&gt;Google Experience&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;android&quot;&gt;Android&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Ice Cream Sandwich to KitKat, Google has not stopped making Android better. One can’t help but view the Apple versus Google rivalry as a modern day replay of Microsoft versus Apple through the eighties and nineties. Let’s face it, Microsoft have made too many missteps in the last 7 years. It’s going to take a radical series of changes to bring Microsoft back. I watched the Surface Pro 2 keynote and laughed at how apologetic they were for the first Surface Pro’s shortcomings - of which there were &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; many. Apple is no longer the constantly-innovating underdog. They are the safe, stable, and very predictable, billion dollar powerhouse. They have gotten too comfortable. Google has never been better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I use, and love, Google’s products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It really is that simple. I could stop this post right here, but I won’t, yet. It may be obvious but Apple and Google couldn’t be more different when it comes to vision and execution. &lt;strong&gt;Steve Jobs&lt;/strong&gt; was a brilliant, truly revolutionary thinker, and he really knew how to execute. Apple has definitely felt the loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;knowing-who-you-are&quot;&gt;Knowing Who You Are&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Google, &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; am the product. To get the most out of the “Google experience”, I need to fully immerse myself into Google’s world. Rather, I need to let Google get to know me. Google probably knows things about me (through data, in some form) that very few people know. But because of this, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/landing/now/&quot; title=&quot;Google Now&quot;&gt;Google Now&lt;/a&gt; provides me with very accurate, sometimes frightening, results. If I purchase something from Amazon, it (Now) will give me shipping notifications. If I frequently search (on Google) for movie showtimes, Google will try to preemptively inform me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Google aims to predict what I want before I give any indication that I want something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where Google starts getting interesting, and yes, scary. But again, know what you’re getting into and be okay with it - if you are okay with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/nexus/5/&quot; title=&quot;Nexus 5&quot;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; is my next.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Google scares me. I’m okay with being scared. Okay, Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/2013/11/im-a-technology-nerd</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2013/11/im-a-technology-nerd</guid>
        
        <category>all about android</category>
        
        <category>iphone</category>
        
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Top 15 Albums of 2012</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2012/15-twin-shadow-confess.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#15 Twin Shadow - Confess&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;twin-shadow---confess&quot;&gt;#15 Twin Shadow - Confess&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-five-seconds-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Five Seconds&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/51888563&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure how I missed George Lewis Jr.’s debut record, 2010’s &lt;strong&gt;Forget&lt;/strong&gt;, but I’m glad I didn’t miss this one. He isn’t saying anything profound, lyrically. But he breathes new life into 80s music stylings, giving enough of a twist to seem relevant today. People have compared his voice to &lt;strong&gt;Morrissey&lt;/strong&gt;, which is totally accurate. I also would compare him to &lt;strong&gt;Prince&lt;/strong&gt; (listen to &lt;em&gt;I Don’t Care&lt;/em&gt;). Lewis also shows off a strong &lt;strong&gt;Bowie&lt;/strong&gt; influence throughout (I think of &lt;em&gt;Cat People (Putting Out Fire)&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My love for this album is entirely superficial. I love the 80s throwback atmosphere; particularly the synthesizers, which are all kinds of awesome. I adore the more out-of-place moments too, like the guitar-driven beat of &lt;em&gt;You Call Me On&lt;/em&gt;. This is a really fun record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Golden Light&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;You Call Me On&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The One&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;I Don’t Care&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2012/14-efterklang-piramida.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#14 Efterklang - Piramida&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;efterklang---piramida&quot;&gt;#14 Efterklang - Piramida&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-hollow-mountain-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Hollow Mountain&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/56404347&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Efterklang is totally new to me this year. I discovered them through an &lt;a href=&quot;http://rdio.com&quot; title=&quot;Get Rdio&quot;&gt;Rdio&lt;/a&gt; recommendation, and man do I dig this record. They remind me of a modern &lt;strong&gt;Talk Talk&lt;/strong&gt;, in composition and feel, mixed with a bit of &lt;strong&gt;The National&lt;/strong&gt;’s vocal/lyric stylings, and a comparison to &lt;strong&gt;Talking Heads&lt;/strong&gt; wouldn’t be out of line. I find their intimate compositions very charming, and almost tailor-fit for winter. This is definitely headphone-recommended music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Hollow Mountain&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Apples&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Black Summer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2012/13-fiona-apple-idler-wheel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#13 Fiona Apple - The Idler Wheel...&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fiona-apple---the-idler-wheel&quot;&gt;#13 Fiona Apple - The Idler Wheel…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-left-alone-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Left Alone&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/66941102&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret I love Fiona Apple. You could say she has a uniquely negative view of the world - based on the lyrics to pretty much every song she’s ever written. She’s tortured, odd, and I kind of adore her for all of it. I’ll put aside the fact that I find dark, and somewhat disturbed women attractive. This woman can sing, and play the shit out of the piano. Her compositions are jarring, unusual, and always technically astute. Most importantly, she sings and performs with deep conviction - scary conviction. She’s unlike any female making music today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Every Single Night&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Daredevil&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Jonathan&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Werewolf&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2012/12-neurosis-honor-found-in-decay.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#12 Neurosis - Honor Found In Decay&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;neurosis---honor-found-in-decay&quot;&gt;#12 Neurosis - Honor Found In Decay&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-we-all-rage-in-gold-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;We All Rage in Gold&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/71661065&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any album Neurosis releases will end up on my year end list of favorite albums. It took me years to appreciate their abrasive, and totally inaccessible approach to creating music. Somewhere around &lt;strong&gt;Times Of Grace&lt;/strong&gt; their music clicked with me. I wouldn’t say they create music for every day consumption, but man, these guys scratch an itch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;At The Well&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;My Heart For Deliverance&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Casting Of The Ages&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2012/11-gojira-lenfant-sauvage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#11 Gojira - L&#39;Enfant Sauvage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gojira---lenfant-sauvage&quot;&gt;#11 Gojira - L’Enfant Sauvage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-explosia-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Explosia&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/68139000&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gojira are just flat-out one of my favorite metal bands today. They continue to exude everything I love about metal. Years ago I dismissed them as a &lt;strong&gt;Meshuggah&lt;/strong&gt; clone, but man was I foolish. To me, Gojira blows Meshuggah away in almost every way - at least on the basis of Meshuggah’s output after &lt;em&gt;Destroy Erase Improve&lt;/em&gt;. Gojira compose technically impressive arrangements that always throw in a bit of a curve ball. Balls to the wall awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;L’Enfant Sauvage&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Axe&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Gift Of Guilt&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Fall&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2012/10-polica-give-you-the-ghost.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#10 Polica - Give You The Ghost&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;polica---give-you-the-ghost&quot;&gt;#10 Polica - Give You The Ghost&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-dark-star-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Dark Star&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/22383886&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote about seeing &lt;a href=&quot;/2012/08/polica-live-at-the-cabooze-outdoor-plaza-81112&quot; title=&quot;Polica Live&quot;&gt;Polica&lt;/a&gt; live a few months back. That post pretty much sums up the way I feel about them. Their debut record has stuck with me throughout the year, which to me is a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I See My Mother&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Dark Star&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Maker&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Lay Your Cards Out&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2012/9-the-kyteman-orchestra.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#9 The Kyteman Orchestra - S/T&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-kyteman-orchestra---st&quot;&gt;#9 The Kyteman Orchestra - S/T&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-the-mushroom-cloud-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;The Mushroom Cloud&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/42017624&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strings, chants, opera, and spoken word. These are elements found on the latest offering from The Kyteman Orchestra. &lt;strong&gt;Colin Benders&lt;/strong&gt; has assembled quite the impressive genre-spanning orchestra. The ensemble consists of eighteen musicians, including opera singers and choir members. According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://kyteman.com/about&quot; title=&quot;Kyteman&#39;s Website&quot;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt;, all instrumentation on this album was recorded in one take, with little editing. That is an extremely impressive feat.
Lyrically, Bender rhymes about existential topics with a shifting delivery method. He gets filthy on several tracks (&lt;em&gt;Truth or Dare&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Angry At The World&lt;/em&gt;). On the opposite end of genre spectrum, &lt;em&gt;Long Lost Friend&lt;/em&gt; is a slow-paced jazz soul track that builds beautifully. &lt;em&gt;Angry At The World&lt;/em&gt; has an insane climax that rivals passion found in the world’s most aggressive rappers. This is such a massive album; one which demands countless listens to take in. I’m in so much awe. What a diverse monster. I highly recommend this record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Truth Or Dare&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Angry At The World&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Long Lost Friend&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Mushroom Cloud&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2012/8-graveyard-lights-out.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#8 Graveyard - Lights Out&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;graveyard---lights-out&quot;&gt;#8 Graveyard - Lights Out&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-endless-night-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Endless Night&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/64849916&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve loved everything these guys have put out. &lt;strong&gt;Lights Out&lt;/strong&gt; hasn’t been as instantly lovable as last year’s brilliant &lt;strong&gt;Hisingen Blues&lt;/strong&gt;, but it’s growing on me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Slow Motion Countdown&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Endless Night&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Goliath&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Fool in the End&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2012/7-katatonia-dead-end-kings.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#7 Katatonia - Dead End Kings&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;katatonia---dead-end-kings&quot;&gt;#7 Katatonia - Dead End Kings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-hypnone-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Hypnone&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/78298236&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Katatonia have had a history of crafting albums that become my go-to jams throughout the winter months. They have pioneered a unique blend of pop-friendly doom metal. It’s very much rooted in doom, but has enough polish, and catchy songwriting to be accessible by the masses. For some reason I still love everything these guys put out. &lt;strong&gt;Dead End Kings&lt;/strong&gt; doesn’t venture outside of charted territory, but continues to hone the brilliant execution of their last two albums &lt;strong&gt;The Great Cold Distance&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Night Is The New Day&lt;/strong&gt;.
Lyrically, there is nothing new here either. All songs continue to revolve around haunting relationships and vaguely depressive feelings, sandwiched between very memorable choruses. &lt;strong&gt;Jonas Renkse’s&lt;/strong&gt; vocals continue getting better than ever. Katatonia stand out against similar acts because of Renske’s vocal ability, and the whole band’s collective musicianship. Katatonia have become better than ever at crafting incredibly intricate songs. When you take a close look at their compositions, it’s hard to deny just how incredible they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Parting&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The One You Are Looking For Is Not Here&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Racing Heart&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Leech&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2012/6-witchcraft-legend.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#6 Witchcraft - Legend&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;witchcraft---legend&quot;&gt;#6 Witchcraft - Legend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-its-not-because-of-you-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;It’s Not Because of You&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/54588580&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These guys put out stellar throwback 70s rock. This album is so damn solid. I’m a sucker for sludgy guitars, wicked solos, and higher register rock vocals. I commend Witchcraft for crafting such a concise record full of sexy ass grooves. This record helps gets me through chaotic web design/development days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Flag of Fate&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;It’s Not Because Of You&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Ghost House&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;White Light Suicide&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2012/5-grizzly-bear-shields.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#5 Grizzly Bear - Shields&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;grizzly-bear---shields&quot;&gt;#5 Grizzly Bear - Shields&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-yet-again-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Yet again&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/55087633&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grizzly Bear is the kind of band that make records I love on first listen, but rarely leave a lasting impact. 2009’s &lt;strong&gt;Veckatimest&lt;/strong&gt; was critically praised, and I dug it quite a bit for a while. At the end of the year it did not make this list. So for me, &lt;strong&gt;Shields&lt;/strong&gt; is the best Grizzly Bear record to date. I feel like everything came together. It is still very much an album to play in the background; to zone out to while doing other things. But it also stands up to the headphone listening experience, as an extraordinary record. The production and vocal execution are top notch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Speak in Rounds&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Yet Again&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Gun-Shy&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Sun In Your Eyes&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2012/4-pos-we-dont-even-live-here.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#4 P.O.S - We Don&#39;t Even Live Here&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pos---we-dont-even-live-here&quot;&gt;#4 P.O.S - We Don’t Even Live Here&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-fuck-your-stuff-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Fuck Your Stuff&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/59488329&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This album was possibly my most anticipated record of the year. After a few listens, I was very underwhelmed. After a few months, I’m still a bit underwhelmed. It has some incredible songs, and some that simply fall a bit short. All things considered, I would be remiss in its exclusion from this list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a difficult task for any musician to follow up such an instant masterpiece as 2009’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://joetower.com/2009/02/pos-never-better-album-review&quot; title=&quot;My Review of Never Better&quot;&gt;Never Better&lt;/a&gt;. P.O.S has made some interesting decisions on this record.
&lt;em&gt;Bumper&lt;/em&gt; is a solid album opener. &lt;em&gt;Fuck Your Stuff&lt;/em&gt; is a banger, but could be a bit heavy-handed, lyrically. Whenever rappers start throwing out heaps of bravado about their “crew” I get a bit uncomfortable. &lt;em&gt;Where We Land&lt;/em&gt; was love at first listen. The lyrics are fantastic. To me, the song is almost like a rap interpretation of the charming 2009 film &lt;em&gt;Away We Go&lt;/em&gt; - which I really liked. But I’m a romantic at heart, and constantly challenge where I choose to live. I’m always trying to find my place.
&lt;em&gt;Wanted/Wasted&lt;/em&gt; is equally incredible. The piano chord progression setting up the hook is just perfectly sick. I give props to &lt;strong&gt;Astronautalis&lt;/strong&gt; too. Love that guy. &lt;em&gt;They Can’t Come&lt;/em&gt; has a bit more lethargic progression, but I dig it overall. &lt;strong&gt;Sims’&lt;/strong&gt; verse is pretty dope, and is another shining example of how far he’s come. 
&lt;em&gt;Lock-Picks, Knives, Bricks and Bats&lt;/em&gt; feels like a &lt;strong&gt;Never Better&lt;/strong&gt; b-side. It’s a great song. I also really dig &lt;em&gt;Fire In The Hole/Arrow To The Action&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this point on it gets a little murky for me. &lt;em&gt;Get Down&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t make me want to get down. It makes me want to skip to the next track. &lt;em&gt;All Of It&lt;/em&gt; rubs me the wrong way too. &lt;em&gt;We Don’t Even Live Here (Weird Friends)&lt;/em&gt; continues the theme of anxiety laden beats, and full-force barrage of lyrics. The album closer &lt;em&gt;Piano Hits&lt;/em&gt; continues the erratic pace set by the latter half of the record. I do like this track, and feel it works well as a closer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I guess with the exception of 3 tracks, I really dig this album. It’s definitely Stef’s most “fun” record to date. While I prefer the more introspective/personal side of P.O.S, I respect how fun he’s tried to make this record. It will hold a place in my record collection, but somewhere beneath &lt;strong&gt;Ipecac Neat&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Never Better&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Where We Land&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Wanted/Wasted&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Lock-Picks, Knives, Bricks and Bats&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Fire In The Hole/Arrow To The Action&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2012/3-macklemore-ryan-lewis-the-heist.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#3 Macklemore &amp;amp; Ryan Lewis - The Heist&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;macklemore--ryan-lewis---the-heist&quot;&gt;#3 Macklemore &amp;amp; Ryan Lewis - The Heist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-cant-hold-us-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Can’t Hold Us&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/21199445&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their perfectly timed gay marriage anthem &lt;em&gt;Same Love&lt;/em&gt; made this duo ## 1 on iTunes, and got them the opportunity to reach a national audience with performances on &lt;strong&gt;Ellen&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Late Night With Jimmy Fallon&lt;/strong&gt;. More importantly, it gave these two Shark Face Gang fools the attention of hip-hop lovers everywhere. I couldn’t be happier they made it into a global spotlight. They deserve it 100%. &lt;strong&gt;The Heist&lt;/strong&gt; is the kind of debut record artists dream about making. &lt;em&gt;Thrift Shop&lt;/em&gt; is a hispter’s anthem, but carries enough charm for me to bump it and not be ashamed. The beat is out of control. &lt;em&gt;Same Love&lt;/em&gt; could be the definitive gay marriage anthem, and I wholly agree with its message.
&lt;em&gt;Neon Cathedral&lt;/em&gt; battles alcoholism with its parody of a bar being his church. These guys are full of energy, positive messages, and pretty excellent production. Ryan Lewis murders every beat on this monster of an album. I have to hand it to all the guest spots too. Every single one is just destroyed - from &lt;em&gt;Same Love&lt;/em&gt;’s &lt;strong&gt;Mary Lambert&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;Allen Stone’s&lt;/strong&gt; soulful execution on &lt;em&gt;Neon Cathedral&lt;/em&gt;. I love this record, hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Can’t Hold Us&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Thrift Shop&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Same Love&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Neon Cathedral&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2012/2-aesop-rock-skelethon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#2 Aesop Rock - Skelethon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;aesop-rock---skelethon&quot;&gt;#2 Aesop Rock - Skelethon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-cycles-to-gehenna-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Cycles To Gehenna&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/57063793&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skelethon is one crazy ride of an album. I’d say it’s his most ambitious record to date. He is still the “&lt;strong&gt;David Lynch&lt;/strong&gt; of this rap shit” - as I describe him. I’ve said it before, but Aesop’s strength as a lyricist has everything to do with how abstractly he writes. At times, strings of fragmented thoughts fly by ignored, and other times those same passages will stick with you. Aesop is not necessarily recommended for a casual hip-hop fan, and people can be off-put by his verbose strings of diarrhea rap. I’ve always lapped that shit up (how’s that for a disgusting pun?).
If you can keep up with some of his (more clearly defined) storytelling-driven narratives, there are a plethora of rewards to be found. This can be a difficult task, given how densely packed each track is (&lt;em&gt;ZZZ Top&lt;/em&gt;). Luckily, Aesop gives you all the lyrics. Though, this can be a daunting task in itself. Sometimes I’m in the mood to dissect and speculate on what he’s trying to say in any given song. Other times I just sit back and enjoy the auditory haze, basking in the always stellar production. For Skelethon, Aesop kept all the production to himself - save some instrumentation collaboration here and there.
This album does feel more personal than previous work. The album title itself is dark, and aptly titled, given the bleak subject matter. Aesop said he was inspired/haunted by all the death that has surrounded him over the past few years; the fundamental truth that everything living dies. He seems to have been in a secluded, self-prescribed hole of mourning while writing this. I hope he mustered up the courage to pull himself out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;ZZZ Top&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Cycles To Gehenna&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Fryerstarter&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Grace&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/best-of-2012/1-frank-ocean-channel-orange.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;#1 Frank Ocean - Channel Orange&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;frank-ocean---channel-orange&quot;&gt;#1 Frank Ocean - Channel Orange&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-pyramids-from-this-record&quot;&gt;Listen to “&lt;em&gt;Pyramids&lt;/em&gt;” from this record:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/49080453&amp;amp;color=ff6600&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;show_artwork=false&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had no problem arriving at this album being my favorite of the year. Since its release in July, I’ve been consistently blown away with each listen. Frank has this unique ability to take seemingly mediocre lyrics and execute them with such a vulnerably personal sincerity. He writes and composes with a wisdom and maturity far beyond his years. This is one of the most well-crafted, well-executed albums I’ve heard in a long time. Calling it a masterpiece is a good start, but doesn’t quite give it adequate praise.
This album represents everything I deeply love about music. It has everything. Now if only it would be released on vinyl - &lt;em&gt;seriously, WTF?&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite tracks:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Thinking Bout You&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Lost&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Pink Matter&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Forrest Gump&lt;/em&gt;, and my favorite song of the year &lt;em&gt;Pyramids&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;looking-forward-2013&quot;&gt;Looking forward: 2013&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;### D’Angelo
In 2013 I’m hoping we see a new D’angelo record. It’s been 12 years since the masterpiece &lt;em&gt;Voodoo&lt;/em&gt; was released. The brilliance of that release isn’t lost a bit on me today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cecil-otter&quot;&gt;Cecil Otter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cecil is probably my 2nd favorite emcee in the Doomtree crew. I need a follow-up to 2006’s/2008’s Rebel Yellow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;earl-sweatshirt&quot;&gt;Earl Sweatshirt&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need a debut full-length from this guy. I’ve listened to &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pitchfork.com/news/48822-watch-the-video-for-earl-sweatshirts-chum/&quot; title=&quot;Earl Sweatshirt - Chum Video&quot;&gt;Chum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; a ridiculous amount of time in the last month. Give me an album, please.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2012 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/2012/12/top-15-albums-of-2012</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2012/12/top-15-albums-of-2012</guid>
        
        <category>top albums of the year</category>
        
        <category>best albums of 2012</category>
        
        <category>top albums of 2012</category>
        
        <category>album reviews</category>
        
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        <category>reviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On Turning 30</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-healthier-me&quot;&gt;A Healthier Me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yep, I turned 30 and found myself looking at my life in a more serious way than before; and arriving at many significant conclusions in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I don’t know how to cook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worse than not cooking, I’ve made terrible food choices my whole life. Growing up, my parents never promoted healthy eating. In a way, I never learned how to eat healthy. I knew damn well that eating fast/frozen foods weren’t good choices. I just never cared to do anything about it. Cooking intimidated me, and stupidly, I hated dirty dishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m learning how to cook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some time in August I decided enough was enough. I radically changed my diet, and have never felt better. No more frozen entrees, frozen pizza, or any other sodium-filled, high calorie, packaged food product. That trash has been replaced by fresh fruits, vegetables, nuts, hummus, and lean meats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;this-is-my-meal-plan-most-days&quot;&gt;This is my meal plan most days:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breakfast:&lt;/strong&gt; A slice of whole wheat bread with creamy natural peanut butter on top, a banana, and 2 servings of carrots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lunch:&lt;/strong&gt; A sandwich filled with (lots of) spinach, turkey, hummus, a few cucumber slices (sometimes), 2 slices of cheese, and 4-5 Kashi 7 Grain Sea Salt Pita Chips (totally makes the sandwich).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dinner:&lt;/strong&gt; A serving of lean ground turkey (spiced up), raw unblanched almonds, walnuts, unsalted sunflower seeds, and shredded cheese heaped on top of a full serving of spinach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snacks:&lt;/strong&gt; An apple, raw unblanched almonds, bananas, or yogurt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to try new recipes in 2013, and figure out how to cook more refined dishes - but still with an emphasis on health. To date I’ve lost 40 pounds. Losing 20 more will get me to an ideal weight for my height. Who knew that losing weight was as easy as changing your diet? It is that easy. I’ve always struggled with weight. That struggle had everything to do with what (and how much) I was eating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;portion-control&quot;&gt;Portion Control&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eating healthy goes hand-in-hand with portion control. As Americans, every one of us is inundated with gluttonous food portions. Fast food is an easy solution; it tastes good, and it’s cheap. When you start eating nutrition-rich food, your stomach and body take notice. I rarely eat fast food now days, and when I do, it’s not great. My tastes have changed. Eating healthy tastes better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Duh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources-that-helped-me&quot;&gt;Resources That Helped Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.livestrong.com/&quot; title=&quot;Livestrong&quot; class=&quot;icon-link&quot;&gt;livestrong.com&lt;/a&gt; came up in google searches for almost every food-related question I had. From wondering why I felt dizzy the first week or so after changing my diet (due to caloric deficit), to how to get enough nutrition as a vegetarian, Livestrong has information for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://movies.netflix.com/WiMovie/Forks_Over_Knives/70185045?trkid=7644894&quot; title=&quot;Forks Over Knives on Netflix&quot; class=&quot;icon-link&quot;&gt;Forks Over Knives&lt;/a&gt; is a great documentary about the benefits of eating all plant-based foods over meat. It provided me with many “ah ha” moments. One such moment was how your body produces insulin, and how it can become resistant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://movies.netflix.com/WiMovie/Fat_Sick_Nearly_Dead/70173634?trkid=7644894&quot; title=&quot;Fat, Sick, and Nearly Dead on Netflix&quot; class=&quot;icon-link&quot;&gt;Fat, Sick, and Nearly Dead&lt;/a&gt; follows 2 men who are overweight, battle diseases, and generally live unhealthy lives. Their story is a catalyst of inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://movies.netflix.com/WiMovie/Fat_Head/70115017?trkid=2361637&quot; title=&quot;Fat Head on Netflix&quot; class=&quot;icon-link&quot;&gt;Fat Head&lt;/a&gt; is a rebuttal, of sorts, to Morgan Spurlock’s film Supersize Me. This film is way better than Supersize Me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://movies.netflix.com/WiMovie/Vegucated/70245084?trkid=7644894&quot; title=&quot;Vegucated on Netflix&quot; class=&quot;icon-link&quot;&gt;Vegucated&lt;/a&gt; examines three meat eaters going through the process of becoming vegan. Watching this film and Forks Over Knives made me seriously question if I want to continue consuming meat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Don’t make a resolution to do something. Just do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mini-vacations-over-staycations&quot;&gt;Mini Vacations Over Staycations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have an inner struggle and harsh dialogue with myself every winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m constantly asking myself “why the hell do you still live in Minnesota?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easy answer is that I love my neighborhood, my family, and the friends I’ve made. Which is also all the reasons I’ve chosen not to move, yet. I still long to live in a more mild winter climate, and would like to be able to further limit reliance on a car for transportation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;austin&quot;&gt;Austin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I took a mini trip to Austin, TX. Austin was the first on a short list of cities I want to visit - to see if I’d want to move away from Minnesota. I didn’t latch-on to Austin as I hoped, but I will be returning in the summer time to see just how hot it gets. It seems like a fantastic place to live, but I’m not sure if it’s awesome enough to leave comfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-york&quot;&gt;New York&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan on visiting New York some time in 2013. I’ll see good friends and learn a bit about what it might be like to live there. One big draw to New York is the walkability. I definitely wouldn’t notice a climate change, but being extra active would be nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;grandma-tower&quot;&gt;Grandma Tower&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My grandmother passed away this year. She was 95 years old, just a few weeks shy of 96. It was hard saying goodbye, but I had been preparing to hear the bad news for years. She lived an incredible life. I feel very grateful to have had such a thoughtful, caring, and truly beautiful human being in my life for 30 years. This post is for my grandmother. A woman who wanted nothing more for me than happiness. Thank you, grandma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-conclusion&quot;&gt;In Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2012 was probably the most personally significant year I’ve had in my adult life. Losing a family member is always difficult, but it is life. Here’s to 2013 being the best year ever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/2012/12/on-turning-30</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2012/12/on-turning-30</guid>
        
        <category>health</category>
        
        <category>diet</category>
        
        <category>food</category>
        
        <category>vegetables</category>
        
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
